DEBORA CRISTINA FONTANELLA

FULLSTACK ENGINEER

Porto, Portugal I fcristinadebora@gmail.com I linkedin.com/in/dcfontanella

SUMMARY

Fullstack developer with 7 years of experience, working with companies building software on demand from end to end, also building and maintaining e-commerce, web applications (SaaS) for companies in different segments. Customer and user support and service, including troubleshooting, training, planning meetings, managing and organizing requests.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Specialization

Pontifícia Universidade Católica (2021-2023)

• Software Engineering Bachelor

Universidade do Contestado (2017-2020)

Computers Programming Technical Course

Centro Paula Souza (2013-2014)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Engineer

DBServices Portugal I Inventsys (2022 - Present)

Activities: Planning, building and maintaining a B2B web application for facilities maintenance management. Applying knowledge of front-end and back-end development, software testing, agile methodologies (Scrum and Kanban), Git flow, CI/CD, databases and AWS cloud.

Technologies: PHP, Symfony Framework, PHPUnit, Codeception, AWS Cloud, Linux, Git, Bitbucket, JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJs, HTML, CSS, Robot Framework.

Backend Engineer

DBServices Portugal I Barkyn (2021 - 2022)

Activities: Planning, building and maintaining an e-commerce web application with subscription service in B2C model, also working on back-office applications such as Prestashop and related internal services. Support in migration to Shopify by building plugins and serverless functions.

Skills: PHP, MySQL, NodeJs, AWS Cloud, AWS Lambdas, Slim Framework, REST APIs, Git, Docker, AWS Cloud, Linux, Jenkins, Microservices Architecture, CI/CD, Agile methodologies.

Teacher

SENAC Santa Catarina (2021 - 2022)

Activities: Planning and execution of classes about Object Oriented Programming for beginners with Python.

• Fullstack Engineer

Compufácil Software (2020 - 2021)

Activities: Build and maintain web application (SaaS) for retail companies's management and invoice generation; integration with government and third party web services.

Skills: PHP, PostgreSQL, MySQL, JavaScript, AngularJS, Laminas Framework, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Git, VueJS, Shellscript, Microservices, Docker, AWS Cloud, Linux, Agile methodologies.

Fullstack Engineer

Inove Sistemas e Soluções Empresariais (2018 – 2020)

Activities:

- Analysis, design and development of a web application to manage the administrative processes
 of logistics companies, as well as other internal and external support applications and web
 services;
- Implementation of Scrum methodology and usage of Git tools;
- Customer and user support and service, including troubleshooting, training, planning meetings, and managing and organizing requests;
- Configuration and management of domains and infrastructure of web servers and databases.

Skills: PHP, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, JQuery, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Codelgniter, Git, VueJs, Lumen Framework, SPA, REST and SOAP.

Fullstack Engineer

O2 Multicomunicação (2017 - 2018)

Activities: Planning and building of websites and web applications, such as e-commerce, content management systems (CMS), ticket sales application and REST APIs. Integrations with payment gateways and marketing automation platforms.

Skills: PHP, HTML, CSS, Laravel, Codelgniter, Javascript, JQuery, VueJs, AngularJs, Git, MySQL, Scrum.